A split weblog entry

Day 00026: Thursday, 2015 April 02

I downloaded a FLAC album from The Kyoto Connection. At the time of writing this, I have not yet converted it to Vorbis, which is a thing I need to do before shipping it to my mobile for later playback.

I just pledged $10 USD per song to Josh Woodward. At that pledge level, he offers to credit you in his videos and link to a URI of your choosing. I have asked that he link back to this site. $10 USD per song is a little steep considering the fact that I usually pay $10 USD *per album*, but I'm calling this a combination good deed and advertising budget expense. When I made the post, Patreon stripped the URI from the sentence it was in, making the sentence a bit incoherent. It seems they added a link to the top of the post, but it's a bit harder to notice so I reposted it. While composing the post, Patreon also grabbed the copyright statement from the bottom of my page and showed it to me, possibly as a warning that I would be answering to the copyright holder (which is myself) if I was misusing the info there.

As I have requested a link back to this place, I needed to clean up the index page. That requires an updating of the site, which results in a premature uploading of this weblog entry. I may add more below after the day is actually over. The canary page will also be updated by this.

[Later today:]

Soon after updating the site, I looked up the code needed to convert the FLAC files to Vorbis format. Speaking of Vorbis format, I'm going to ask Josh Woodward later if he could start uploading his work in Vorbis format again. He used to upload in both Vorbis and MP3 formats, but lately, he has fallen back to only uploading in MP3 format. Now that I'll actually be paying the guy, I feel less bad about begging him to put in that little bit of extra effort. As a downloader of gratis music, I really had no right to ask for more, but as a paying customer, I think I should be allowed to politely ask (though not demand) that he consider using the Vorbis format again. I will wait until he responds to my first request about including a link to this site before commenting on the lack of Vorbis files though. I don't want to seem overly demanding all at once.

I have now taken the final step toward canceling my mobile service. I contacted support and asked how cancellation with that carrier worked. Specifically, I asked if service needed to be explicitly canceled or if failing to pay (the service is prepaid, not postpaid) would kill the account without harmful effects. The carrier sort of asked me for photo ID when I registered, so I don't need some sort of damage done to my reputation. It seems that if the account is not paid, it enters a 60 day period of suspension. After that, the account ends. Alternatively, the customer can contact support and explicitly say they want to cancel the account, and it will be terminated on the spot.

Once my service ends, I will be free to drop off everyone's telephone radar. As I have said before to many people, there are only three groups that I should hand my number over to: my registrars, my current/potential employers, and my mother (She refuses to send SMS to email despite it being far easier to work with on my end. She insists upon sending SMS to my telephone number instead.). My new registrar/registry, nic.st, doesn't even ask for a telephone number and does not put it in the public whois database. As a result, I am no longer required to have a telephone number to hold a domain! I may avoid getting new service altogether, or I may get a number that I keep private, only giving it to employers and my mother. Anyone else that tries to demand I give them my telephone number will simply be told that I do not have a telephone. Even if I decide to get new mobile service, this will technically be true even, as mobile devices are not really telephones at all; they are small computers. They accept calls, but most laptop and desktop machines can accept telephone calls too if equipped with the right software and service for them is paid. That does not in any way make these machines telephones. A computer is simply able to perform a wide variety of tasks and mobile devices come with the needed software preinstalled. Anyway, the telephone number system is idiotic, and until we switch over to SIP addressing or something, I refuse to bind my identity to a telephone number any more than I absolutely have to and no one has the right to try to force me to.

I have now attempted to reach out to GitHub on Twitter, as they won't respond when I try to contact them through the Web form on their site.

I registered on the EFF's website to participate in their campaigns. I had an account before, but I lost it when I lost my passwords on the dead hard drive. Much to my surprise, I found that the net neutrality campaign is over. We've won! Last I knew, the FCC had agreed to reinstate net neutrality, but congress was still potentially going to overrule the FCC. That nightmare is over for the time being though. There may very well be another attack of this magnitude on the Internet again in the future, but for now, the Internet is safe. Some of the EFF's campaign pages require the entry of a telephone number before they will allow submission and send email letters to government representatives. Telephone numbers have nothing to do with email and should not be required. I have written to the EFF about this issue.

Copyright © 2015 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

An ownCloud instance installed

Day 00027: Friday, 2015 April 03

I finally set up my ownCloud instance. I had one before, but it was lost when my hard drive died on me. I was going to download the archive and set it up manually, as I feel this offers the most flexibility in terms of allowing multiple instances and prevents the installation of the configuration file that automatically makes the ownCloud instance available at /owncloud/ on every website hosted by the machine. I mean, honestly, ownCloud should only be present at one location if it is a single instance, not present once for every site hosted. I decided that I don't really need multiple instances of ownCloud and the ownCloud site recommends installation by package.

Since I was going to be installing from a package, I figured I might as well get the most benefit possible from doing that. Updating ownCloud would be easiest if I added the ownCloud repository to Aptitude, so that's what I did. As expected, installing the ownCloud packages caused a configuration file adding ownCloud access to all hosts on the machine, so I removed the symbolic link pointing to that. The ownCloud documentation was helpful for setting up the needed MySQL database. Once installed, I found that the calendar and contacts modules, which had been the reason I installed ownCloud, were seemingly missing. As it turned out, they weren't actually missing though, just disabled by default. Last time I installed ownCloud, it had been from a different repository (the Debian 7 backport repository), so it makes sense that this time it would have different default configuration. Enabling these modules was easy, and everything appears to be in working order.

The obvious places for me to put my ownCloud instance were o.y.st and c.y.st, either way over HTTPS. I decided to use o.y.st, as "oyst" might be short for "oyster" or something, but a cyst is a negative medical condition. c.y.st is still one of my more valuable host names due to its short length, but I will avoid using it for now. With o.y.st taken, it won't be usable for my OpenID server if I ever get around to setting that up, but I might put that at the unpronounceable i.y.st.

My mother asked me about logging that one Geocache event that her friend is trying to get people to log that they will attend. I explained that the Geocaching website is refusing to allow me to log, but tried again with the same results. I have now posted in the Geocaching forum asking for help, but it's doubtful help will arrive. Once the post leaves the moderation queue, I'll likely get bogus responses about how I need to take down my proxy. That is not happening.

I was trying to find PehJota's Jamaldo script, which I would then have to figure out the dependencies to. There are no instructions for set up, and by default, it throws errors due to missing software. The problem is that while PehJota is quite helpful and will tell you what you need if you ask, I keep losing the list of dependencies for one reason or another. I'm getting a bit embarrassed that I have to keep asking. This time, while looking for his script, I instead found a Jamendo album downloader Firefox add-on. For my particular use case (I don't disable JavaScript like I honestly should), this add-on is a bit easier to use. Unfortunately, the source code is hosted on Gitorious, which is disappearing in May. No one has touched the source code since August, and I fear it will get deleted without anyone noticing. I have downloaded the source for safe keeping, and if needed, I will upload it to my Git host once I manage to find a suitable Git host to keep my stuff on. I still recommend Jamaldo if you prefer a command line tool and want your Vorbis comments normalized.

I need to get together a "to do" list at some point. For now, I've jotted down a few things I need to make happen, and I'll add to it as I come up with more.

As of tonight, I am still not being oppressively censored.

*EDIT (2015-12-10)*: This page once held a hyperlink to the "to do" list, but when I moved this website from quystystxtvdgyst.onion. to authorednansyxlu.onion., I did not keep the list public. As such, the link has been removed from this page.

Copyright © 2015 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Cricket has been not been delivering the rebates they have promised

Day 00028: Saturday, 2015 April 04

I tried to log into Patreon today to check and see if Josh Woodward has responded to my URI inclusion request. However, Patreon refuses to allow me to log in! Patreon's log in form is some sort of hacky JavaScript mess and won't submit my log in credentials. No error is returned, the form simply doesn't do anything. I tried disabling JavaScript in my browser to make use of the no script fall back option, but it turns out there *is no* no script fall back option. I have submitted a request for help through Patreon's Web contact form.

At work today, I was manning one of the cash registers. Someone paid using one of the Cricket Wireless rebate cards. I said Oh, so those do exist., and mentioned how the one Cricket promised me still has not arrived. She told me that many people she knew had not been getting theirs, and some even received letters denying their rebate requests, despite their requests being valid. She continued that she had needed to call up Cricket and demand the card, as they had not sent hers either. In other words, Cricket Wireless is lying to people, getting them to buy new devices under the premise that the cost of them will be rebated, but then they are refusing to actually follow through. That's a pretty dishonest way to make money. I held back yesterday when talking about Cricket. I wrote up a paragraph about why I am leaving them, but thought better of it, and dropped it from my weblog entry. Perhaps I should post that paragraph though, which is still saved to my hard drive. If it comes to it, I will get very noisy about this. I will post about all the issues with Cricket here in my weblog and continually poke them on Twitter about their actions. I will not be trampled on.

The Cricket Web interface claims my rebate card was mailed to mo on 2014-10-24. However, it still has not arrived. That was several months ago, and is more than enough time for the card to make it through the mail. I reached out to Cricket support through the Web interface, as I'm really not big on telephone conversations. Web support said they could not help, and redirected me to telephone support. I was told to call 888 326 6178 and choose option 3. Option three was not listed, so I just followed the prompts. The automated system told me that to reach a representative, I would need to call back Monday through Friday, 7 to 19 Central time. I guess I'll call back in two days.

I checked on my Visa card to see if the card had been canceled and replaced yet. According to their records, I made the request on 2015-03-13, but there has still not been a response yet. I will give them until the tenth or eleventh, which is when my mobile service officially ends. If they have not yet responded, I will walk into the credit union again and explain the situation again. If they claim that they cannot mark the card number as compromised, I will ask that they cancel the card altogether. Last time I spoke with them in person, they said I have to call a telephone support line to cancel the card. However, it cannot be legal for them to require me to stay attached to a credit card simply because I do not have a telephone. I will demand to speak with a higher representative if I have to, but I will not submit to requests that I validate the broken telephone number system. Unless you are my employer, you do not have the right to require me to have a telephone.

Since recovering my Discover account, Discover has not been allowing me to update my user name or password. They won't tell me why, but having dealt with their tech support in the past, I'm fairly certain what's going on. It's likely that I recently changed my email address on record with them. So I will wait. Once things are cleared up with my Visa card (be that by marking it as compromised or by canceling the account altogether), I will try again with Discover. Best case scenario: everything works at that point. Worst case scenario: I'm stuck with an outdated user name and a password that, while still secure, is shorter than it could be. Honestly, I don't really lose much.

It appears that GNU Social is hosted on Gitorious. As Gitorious is vanishing in May, that could be bad. It's likely that arrangements to move elsewhere are already being made, and even if they are not, it's unlikely that the FSF would allow the project to vanish. I'm not sure how much of a hand the FSF has in the project's development, but it's one that they seem to care about. At the very least, they would grab a copy of the code and put it on their non-gnu site until a new maintainer is found. However, to be safe, I think I'll keep a copy of the archive as well.

NotMaple of #Volatile told me about a social network offered over Tor called TorBook. I was going to join, but it seems the site requires registrants enter a sex and a date of birth. I don't mind entering a birth year, andI suppose I don't mind entering my sex, but an exact date of birth is too much. No good can come from entering my full date of birth. Most likely, this is used for some sort of feature that draws attention to users' birthdays, and I prefer to ignore my birthday. Birthdays are no more than the anniversary of the day you were born, and anniversaries are completely arbitrary. I prefer to ignore all anniversaries, especially those relating to myself, unless there is some technical reason why the anniversary isn't meaningless after all. For example, the anniversary of a domain name registration becomes its renewal date. At that point, you aren't so much observing the anniversary itself, but instead something that still has meaning and just so happens to fall on the anniversary.

At the end of the day, Patreon finally allowed me to log in, though I'm not sure what changed. Josh Woodward just released a new song called Too Many Valleys, though it seems my URI and I were not included in the YouTube description (which had been the promised reward for pledging $10 USD per song. I'm sure this was just an oversight though, and I have written to Josh Woodward about it.

Today, I speak my mind freely.

Copyright © 2015 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Now I feel like a fool

Day 00029: Sunday, 2015 April 05

Josh Woodward got back to me, and it was my misunderstanding of his system that was to blame. It seems that normally, he waits until funds are sent to him (Patreon send funds at the end of each month), at which point he updates his list of $10 USD or more per song contributors. He then uses this new lists going forward. This means that if someone starts funding him at the beginning of the month as I did, they will not be credited in any songs produced that month. However, the flip side of that is that if someone stops funding him at the beginning of the month, they *will* be credited despite not paying for those songs. I bring this up not as a suggestion of how to abuse an artist, as Josh Woodward is someone that I would very much like to remain a part of the free music community, but as an illustration of how his policy is constant (or seems so from where I see it).

He did add me to the video though, but he did so under my legal name, not my Patreon account name. I have no problem with this whatsoever, though it leads me to wonder where he found my name. Did he visit my site so see what he was linking to? If he had, he'd have seen my name plastered across the top, though only if he visited before the server went down. (My mother took the server down due to a storm. She didn't want another surge killing my remaining hard drive, which would have left me in a pretty desperate state.) If I was going to link to a site, I would want to know what was on it first, though he would have needed to accept the self-signed certificate to get in. Does he get access to the billing information on the credit card I payed him with? My legal name and address would be listed there. Or was he dig a bit and run a whois query on me? I'll probably never know as I do not plan to ask. I'm not exactly hiding, after all.

I apologized to Josh Woodward for the confusion, and I'm sure he'll understand. Still, I feel a bit bad, and to sort of make up for it a little, I've moved his $40 USD music pack to the top of my purchase list. I was going to get a couple other albums first, but Josh Woodward's music pack was defiantly something I wanted to pick up. I certainly won't mind having Wrong Side of the Revolution back in my play list.

Speaking of Josh Woodward's $40 USD music pack, I tried to buy it. However, PayPal is being a pain again. I will argue with them some more. Never mind, scratch that. I wrote up a post to send PayPal's way, but then tried the purchase again before sending it. I have no idea what's going on with PayPal's system as usual, but the purchase has gone through. Now I just wait for the ZIP file containing all Josh Woodward's songs to arrive by email.

According to Wikipedia, dota are not valid as the first or last character of the local part of an email address. This means I have been entering invalid email addresses in Web forms. Most of the time, I end the local part of the address with a dot. The Josh Woodward music pack may not arrive because I unintentionally supplied an invalid address. I do not want to pester Josh Woodward again though, so I will probably stay silent about this. It is, after all, my own fault for supplying an invalid address. Besides, paying for the songs was itself the goal, not acquiring the tunes. Josh Woodward makes his music available gratis in MP3 and (sometimes) Vorbis, so I'll just download the Vorbis albums where available. I don't really *need* the bonus pack, and the FLAC files are available for download individually once you buy the music pack. (Who am I kidding? Eventually I'll be back and I'll buy the music pack again for the bonus pack at some point.).

I had been using the trailing dot as a marker to indicate (to myself) that an email address given was based on the domain of the service I gave the address too. Not every one of my addresses is domain-based, so there needs to be a way to distinguish addresses that are not based on domains and addresses that are based on simply a bare TLD with no second level domain. The chances of collision are small, but I like to avoid setting up needless ambiguity.

After Patreon wrote back to me, I did a bit more testing on my own. Their site was once again refusing to allow me to log in. It seems though that it's just that their JavaScript log in does not like auto-fill. The user must modify the contents of *both* the email address input *and* the password input. If the user relies on auto-fill for either one, the form simply won't submit, silently failing without so much as an error message. I have relayed my findings to the Patreon support team. It won't tell them exactly how to fix it, but it should give them a better idea of where to look than just "your form is busted".

Today, I withhold a little bit of information, but it is not because of government force. Instead, it is because no good can come from the information, but harm might.

Copyright © 2015 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Music and (maybe) money aquired

Day 00030: Monday, 2015 April 06

It turns out that two days ago, when I tried to call Cricket's promotional card processing center number, I transposed the last two digits. As a result, I reached someone else. However, due to the fact that the company that I did reach also being a promotional card processing center, I thought Cricket had simply hired someone to do their card processing. The company I did reach had Cricket's card processing center's number though, which I compared against the number in my weblog which I had copied and pasted from the chat window when I was given it. It matched, proving that it was my error typing the number into the mobile, not Cricket's representative's mistake.

Cricket's call center sounded very much like the one I had accidentally called. It's likely that they are handled by the same company, and I therefor would have had to wait until Monday to call anyway. The representative stood by the story that the card had already been mailed out. He said to call 855-266-8203 and report the card as lost in the mail. At this next call center, I was informed once again that the card had in fact been mailed out already, but also that due to how long ago it had been sent out, it had already expired. The representative agreed to reissue the card and to expect it in twenty-one days. That lands on April 27, which has been added to my notes.

Did the card really get lost in the mail, or are the cards not being sent out in hopes that most people won't pursue them further? I would assume the former if it weren't for that customer the other day telling me about how no one she knows has been getting the cards. I asked one of my bosses about her expected card, and she had not received one either. The fact that they expire and cannot be changed for cash is pretty shady as well. It's clear that they don't want you to use the funds in time. By the time my "new" card is due to arrive, I will not have telepone service to report if it hasn't. Hopefully walking into a brick and mortar Cricket location will work if it comes down to it.

Josh Woodward contacted me about the lost email containing download links to his music. He recognized both that it was a spam trap address and that the dot at the end made the address invalid. As I said yesterday, I was a bit too embarrassed by yesterday to write to him about it, but the fact that he wrote to me about it and knew what he was talking about really made my day. Via Patreon private message, he sent the five links that would have been in the email had I not used an invalid address format.

Josh Woodward sending me those links really made my day after having had to spend the off-work part of the day dealing with people over stupid telephony.

Today I speak freely, not a care in the world.

Copyright © 2015 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

A peek inside the proverbial treasure chest

Day 00031: Tuesday, 2015 April 07

The first of Josh Woodward's ZIP files finished downloading late last night, but I didn't have time to examine its contents much until today. The ZIP file appears to be too large for either Xarchiver or Xfce's "Extract Here" option. Xarchiver simply hangs unresponsively, appearing to be frozen. Xfce's "Extract Here" silently fails. My guess is there is just so much stuff in the ZIP file that these programs can't handle it. As usual, unzip on the command line works flawlessly.

Once the files were extracted, I noticed that despite this being the full FLAC version ZIP file, several MP3s were present. The first thing I did was sort all the files using Ex Falso to make them easier to look through. Five files had renaming conflicts due to sharing titles: JoshWoodward-AmaranthineYouFly-2.mp3, JoshWoodward-AmaranthineYouFly-3.mp3, JoshWoodward-DeadCode-3.mp3 JoshWoodward-DeadCode-4.mp3, and JoshWoodward-DeadCode.mp3. The last three were obviously Josh Woodward's song Dead Code, which while is an awesome, nerdy, up-beat tune, is one I've heard before. The former two were of more immediate interest, because I've never heard that song. As the file names imply and the files' meta data confirm, they contain a song called Amaranthine, You Fly. I have never heard of this song before, and it is not one that Josh seems to sell on his website aside from in this bundle.

I listened to JoshWoodward-AmaranthineYouFly-2.mp3 first, and found it to be a haunting and beautiful instrumental song. I believed this to be the full song, not an instrumental version, as it was in the full version ZIP, but upon listening to JoshWoodward-AmaranthineYouFly-3.mp3, I found the song does have lyrics after all. I also listened to the Dead Code files, finding JoshWoodward-DeadCode-3.mp3 to be instrumental, while JoshWoodward-DeadCode-4.mp3 and JoshWoodward-DeadCode.mp3 were the full version. On the command line, I used diff to verify that the two with-vocals Dead Code files were identical. Based on this, I think that the number appended to the file names represent how complete the song is. the "4" version of Dead Code became the final, while the "3" version didn't yet have vocals. In that case, the "2" version of Amaranthine, You Fly isn't missing vocals because it's the instrumental version, but because it's a snapshot from before the vocals were added. A FLAC copy of the complete song is included, so I'll conver that to Vorbis and probably not touch the MP3s again. I might grab the instrumental version from the instrumental FLAC ZIP file though because of how lovely it is. Why does Josh not sell this song along with the others though? It's a very beautiful piece and I think a lot of people would buy it.

Next, I went through the albums to sort out the files that corresponded to Vorbis files I already have. I will keep the FLAC files in storage in case I decide to create directive works or use them in videos or something, but for now, my goal was to find the FLAC files that have no Vorbis counterpart on the site and create one to add to my music player. While doing this, I noticed that there was no "Here Today" album, but instead, a "Here Today (Remixed)" album. I can't hear any audible difference between the songs in "Here Today" and "Here Today (Remixed)", but the songs differ in length by a couple seconds. I kind of wonder if "Here Today (Remixed)" is a legacy album title from near when Josh first redid his older albums. The FLAC files may not have been updated because they don't get seen as often. I debated about putting both versions on my player, but they are for all intents and purposes identical, so I stuck with "Here Today", as it is already in Vorbis version.

Next, I found the "She Lost Her Wings" and "California Lullaby (Single)" albums, both of which contained only a single MP3 file. I opted instead to just use the "The Beautiful Machine" album, which contains both singles and is in FLAC format. I imagine these singles were likely released prior to The Beautiful Machine being released. It's likely that all the singles Josh has been releasing lately will likewise find their way onto the next album. "Ashes" and "The Beautiful Machine", my two missing Woodward albums, were included in FLAC format. "Gangnam Style" contained a single MP3, and "Unreleased" contained nothing but MP3s. Many of the songs in Unreleased were already added to The Beautiful Machine, so I just kept the copy from the FLAC The beautiful Machine.

Lastly, I went through the files that were not part of an album, most of them due to missing album/song title meta data. Again, I found many duplicates between the missing-meta FLAC files and the "Unreleased" MP3s. I kept the FLAC files, and my sorting was at last done. One file I expected to see, but didn't, was the alternate version of Golden Sunrise. It appears this version is reserved for people that sign up for Josh's mailing list and is available only in MP3 format. Ex Falso messes up the file names of any file missing a track title if the title is used in the naming pattern, so I fixed the file names on these files. I don't exactly understand the syntax of find . -name "*flac" -exec oggenc {} \;, but I used it to convert the files to Vorbis, then added the new music to my player.

I will save the next ZIP file for another treasure hunt tomorrow.

Josh Woodward also released several new songs today. I can't really comment on them due to my line being tied up by the continuing download of his ZIPs. (They should be finished downloading by tomorrow.) The first is only a preview, so if you want to hear it, you'll need to join his Patreon fund-raising. The second is The Rival Within. After posting these two songs, he sent out links to The Rival Within, Too Many Valleys (the song from the other day), and a new one called Honeyed Tongue, a song present in the ZIP file but which I had not heard about before. I tried to load the videos to the songs, but the connection was just too busy. I did, however, notice that in the "related videos" section, a video for "Amaranthine, You Fly" showed up. I'm not sure why it wasn't available on Josh's website at the time I checked for it, but it's not a secret song and very likely will be added to the site if it has not been already.

Nothing happened today that the government is interested in trying to get me to hide. I pretty much just explored awesome music files, unable to get online much due to continued downloading.

Copyright © 2015 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Please don't send me pizzas. I can't eat meat or cheese.

Day 00033: Thursday, 2015 April 09

Twidere quit functioning on me after the update last night. I've uninstalled it and installed AndStatus. It may take a bit to get used to the differences, but it should work just fine. It certainly has one thing going for it at the very least: unlike the new version of Twidere, it doesn't crash every time it is started.

Speaking of glitches and malfunctions, it seems my mobile has taken up the habit of spazing out if it has been powered on too long. I haven't been paying attention to exactly the length of time, but it takes at least several days before any issues occur. Once problems arise, rebooting fixes everything. Why does my mobile have to reboot periodically? It's not running Windows, after all.

Someone sent a Domino's pizza to my door under my legal name. Later, while I was away from home, apparently Pizza Hut also tried to deliver, though no one was home to receive the pizzas. we had just been discussing the availability of my postal address in my whois records on #Volatile, and the timing lines up a little too well. I received email confirmations from both orders, and both were sent to the email address from my contact page, an email address I have never posted anywhere but there and have never used in the physical world. This means that the people sending these orders got my address and name from my whois records (or from the channel when someone posted a partial copy of my whois records there), but got my email address from my contact page, not the whois records. Please don't send me pizzas though, I'm vegan and cannot eat meat or cheese. Much food was wasted today. Both orders were placed using different bogus telephone numbers, leading me to believe that two separate people were pranking me, not just one person pranking me with two orders.

On #Volatile, donkus asked if I own this domain. This statement here acts as proof that I do (though donkus said no proof was needed).

Today, no one prevents me from speaking my mind.

Copyright © 2015 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

The ISPs are at it again...

Day 00034: Friday, 2015 April 10

USTelecom and Alamo Broadband are now suing the FCC to once again try to overturn net neutrality. USTelecom claims that they are only trying to restore things to the way they were before, when the FCC had a lighter touch in regulating them. However, it is important to note that the FCC *had* issued strong regulations in the past. It was only once Verizon sued the FCC that these rules were deemed unenforcible. By reclassifying Internet service as a Title II service, the FCC gained the legal foothold to enforce the net neutrality rules that had been in place all along. The ISPs aren't trying to regain something lost. They are trying to take what was never theirs and charge websites exorbitant fees to avoid being slowed way down. They claim that they had not slowed down websites before the reclassification, but the reason they had not is because the existing regulation at the time prevented them from doing so. The telecoms are worried that they have been reclassified as public utilities, but here's the thing: they've been public utilities all along, whether technically classified as such or not. Internet access is a public right, and they have no right to break our access to this global network of information exchange.

AndStatus doesn't crash as soon as it opens the way that Twidere does, but instead it crashes the whole device a few seconds after opening the application. That doesn't seem like much of an improvement to me.

It seems the local part of an email address is restricted to sixty-four characters. This poses a potential problem when trying to use a spam trap address with services that use a longer domain name, but hopefully this won't be too big of an issue. Most people try to use domain names with a length well under that limit.

I have contacted GitHub support for the fourth time. There is a chance that my invalid email address format was preventing them from receiving my pleas for help, but we'll see if that actually makes a difference.

Discover accepted my old invalid email address, but does not seem to accept valid addresses with plus signs. As a result, I substituted a tilde, though as my new email address was accepted, Discover quit accepting valid addresses with tildes as well. I think their system is broken. While I was on their site, both before and after updating my email address, I tried to update my user name and password. No dice.

Finally, I figured out why ~/bin shows up in my $PATH when I am on a TTY but when I am using the regular terminal window from the graphical desktop. For login shells, ~/.profile is executed, but for non-login shells, it is not. Instead, ~/.bashrc is executed. Finally understanding the pattern, the fix was easy. ~/.bashrc looks for ~/.bash_aliases, and if it exists, executes it. ~/.bash_aliases seems to therefor act as a place to put your own customizations. This file did not exist, so I created it with the following content, which I copied from the default ~/.profile:

#!/bin/sh

# set PATH so it includes user's private bin if it exists

if [ -d "$HOME/bin" ] ; then

    PATH="$HOME/bin:$PATH"

fi

Now, the ~/bin directory is added to the $PATH as it should be. The obvious down side though is that ~/.profile executes ~/.bashrc, meaning that login shell now have ~/bin in the $PATH twice.

I finally started using a client certificate for authenticating on IRC. Doing so on most networks was straitforward once I figured out how to make client authentication work at all, though on Volatile, you have to use a command not listed by the bot when you ask it for help: /squery sv allow add certfp. This command adds the fingerprint of the client certificate that you are currently using to the access list. One problem though is that HexChat uses the client certificate even for networks that you have not told it to.

Certain people, wowaname especially, get annoyed with the fake lag set by default by many clients. She looked up the command to disable it in HexChat, which is /set net_throttle off.

After a few hours of banging my head on my keyboard, I finally managed to implement typing quirks in a HexChat module. In short, what this means is that I can type the way I normally do, but to everyone else, it will look different. If I can codify the mannerisms and typing style of the characters I pretend to be, I can more easily wear them as masks. Before I dive too deeply into codifying the typing style of my characters, I want to implement a special phrase that, if my client hears, will pull off my mask. Something like "I know you are Yst. I read about your script on <https://y.st/>.", which when said, will force my client to change my nick to Yst and disable the typing quirk. This phrase will be case sensitive and punctuation and spacing will count. So if you are reading this and think I am among you secretly, give me a shout-out!

I am still able to speak freely, both as myself and as any of my practical joke characters.

Copyright © 2015 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

The site is beginning to show some organization

Day 00035: Saturday, 2015 April 11

I finally got the links to the signature files set up on each XHTML page. The "Signature" link in the upper navigation isn't the most obvious place for it, as it looks like it's a link to the same file on every page, but it was the best I could come up with for now. The alternative was to put it down near the bottom with the copyright statement with a description of what the signature was for, but I thought that might make it sound like I am trying to discourage modification of my pages, which very much is not the case. The signature allows you to know it came unmodified from me, but if someone wants to modify and redistribute my work, they by all means should. They simply shouldn't pretend that their version came unmodified from me.

With the signature links out of the way, I was able to clean up the weblog index a bit.There's more to come, but for now, the month view pages now look like little ASCII calendars and you can click on the days to go to the pages they represent. The calendars are built using a custom function and a pair of nested PHP foreach statements, so they mostly update themselves. The custom function is similar to a class I once built, but that class was lost when the hard died on me. The new function is more flexible anyway, as instead of spiting out three dimensional array-objects where the third dimension holds random pieces of information about the calendar days that I thought was useful at the time, it instead spits out two dimensional arrays populated by raw timestamps. This means that the function does no extra processing to obtain data that may not be needed in a given context. It also means that the raw time stamp is available to process in any way that is needed at the time.

The plan with the ASCII calendars is to first move their source into a single file, then extend the calendar-index pages to include pages for the years. The single source file for the calendar pages will basically just look for which directories need to be populated by an index, then glean information from the file names to figure out which month/year the index should represent. The year indexes will pretty much be the same as the month indexes, except that they will have up to twelve calendar pages on them. To aid in placement of these pages to best utilize the space, I'll make them float around a bit with CSS, shifting as needed based on the width of the page.It will be a simple touch that will leave the page still looking mostly unstyled, but it will look better for anyone with CSS enabled in their Web browser. As usual, nothing here will depend on CSS to function, and it will degrade gracefully. If CSS is disabled, calendar pages will not be displayed beside each other, instead being displayed above and below one another.

It's worth noting that the calendars require a fixed-width font to display nicely. Most Web browsers that do not use CSS are text-based browsers, which tend to use a fixed-width font, so I don't anticipate any issues. Graphical Web browser tend to not use fixed-width fonts by default, but the CSS on this site fixes that.

Josh Woodward released another demo today, but I was much too busy to look into it. I haven't had time to check out his other new songs yet either, but if he keeps up these regular updates, I'm sure to not forget about his music that is sitting in my backlog waiting for me to get to it.

GitHub finally got back to me. They confirmed that my other three cries for help did not make it into their system, as I feared. My guess is that their Web form attempts to send the support request via email to some other system with the return address pointing back to the user's in box. Because I had accidentally entered an address in an invalid format, the letter was probably being rejected.

I can't get into Volatile any more. As soon as I join, I am booted from the network for excess flood before I can even say a thing. I think the network has been misconfigured and has started treating my channel joins as messages. I autojoin eighteen channels, so that many "messages" all at once may be considered flooding.

I tried AndStatus one last time, but as before, it crashed my mobile, so I removed it and installed Tinfoil For Twitter. Tinfoil For Twitter's interface seems a bit buggy, though the application just acts as a wrapper for Twitter's mobile site, so it may be Twitter's mobile site that's actually buggy. In any case, Tinfoil For Twitter doesn't seem like a viable option unless I was planning to read only (not retweet). I don't think I saw any other Twitter applications available besides those three. I might try Twitter's mobile site in the stock browser, but if that doesn't work, Twitter on mobile might not work out for me.

Speaking of mobiles, Cricket told me via SMS two nights ago that if I didn't pay them by midnight, they would cut off my service. That was a day ahead of when they were supposed to cut it off, but I wasn't going to fight them over one day. However, the service didn't get cut off anyway. I took this to mean that in the timezone the SMS message was sent from, it was sent after midnight so it really meant that my service was good until the end of tomorrow as it should have been. Now, it has been over 48 hours since I received that message, and I still have service. I'm not complaining, but it's very odd.

I've decided to put my Minetyst project on hold. The truth is, I've been very busy with other things. Even if I did find the time to work on Minetyst though, I wouldn't benefit from it. My current computer overheats way too quickly and shuts off if put under any sort of strain. And Minetest puts that strain on it. I could build minetyst_game and set up a server, but I would be unable to play on it. What would even be the point?

The government has not stolen my right to free speech today.

Copyright © 2015 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.1 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

The weblog index is complete

Day 00036: Sunday, 2015 April 12

I updated the "weblog" link to point directly to /weblog/2015/ instead of /weblog/, as there are no other files in that directory yet, and there won't be for some time.

PHP's dir() function returns an object that cannot be iterated over. The intuitive thing to do is to iterate over the directory with a foreach statement, but that simply cannot be done. Instead, every time I need to iterate over a directory in PHP, I have to look up the proper method to do it again. Tired of this, and still trying to build up my PHP toolbox, I built a simple generator function that can be used in the intuitive way. However when I tested it, I was quickly reminded of the fact that PHP does not return the contents of a directory in the intuitive (alphabetical) order. Instead, the directory contents are returned in whatever order they are stored in on disk. For many use cases, this doesn't matter, but in some, it's a pain to deal with. I reworked the function, changing it from a generator function to a regular function that returns an array of alphabetized file names.

After coding that much-needed function, I set about trying to figure out how I wanted to parse month information out of directory names. I ended up deciding that anything I came up with would cost more computational power than just hard coding the names I use for month directories into my script. It seems messy to do that, but everything else I could come up with was messier. As a result, I ended up not needing the alphabetizing of directory contents for the time being, though it is still nice to have for later. You can't predict what order things will land on the file system, but you can predict the results of an alphabetized listing.

Using CSS a flex box, I set the ASCII calendar pages to display side by side on weblog year index page. At this point, the weblog month index pages are pretty much deprecated. The will continue to exist in case there are any existing links to them and in case someone tries to reach them by deleting the file name from the URI of a weblog entry page, but no links to them will exist on my site any more. Using a flex box introduced a bug in the mobile version of the site due most likely to the mobile browser not supporting flex boxes. This seems strange to me, as small screens are where you would need flex boxes the most. Adding a text-align attribute (which is ignored by Web browsers that support flex boxes) made the mobile version of the site display better, though I don't think it will provide the desired results on larger mobiles, such as tablets.

I did a little experimenting today, and found that Cricket has indeed cut off my telephony properly. However, they have not cut off my data access, and I still have full Internet connectivity. This seems like a huge oversight in their system to me. Personally, I never use telephony if I can at all avoid it. The value of the connection to me lies entirely in the Internet access. I don't know why their system has not cut me off, but I know this is too good to last forever. My guess is that the connection will die completely after the 60 day suspension period has ended.

Another benefit of the new calendar setup for the weblog index is that it acts as a sort of second canary, though this was not at first the intention. I write in my weblog every day, so if any day is missing from the calendar, it will stick out like a sore thumb.

Copyright © 2015 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.1 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Something needs to be done about pinentry

Day 00037: Monday, 2015 April 13

I'm not one of those people that blasts his music all the time. Much of the time, my music is down so low you can't hear the words unless you already know what they are, and when it isn't that low, it's at least at a tolerable level and is easily covered up by any sort of loud noise in the vicinity. For that reason, I often discover new treasures in my playlist, songs that I've heard many times before, but never really payed attention to. Today, Chainsaw was such a song. It's got a slow, mellow melody, so if you aren't paying attention, it's easy to miss the fact that the song is about a psychopathic murderer. The narrator of the song killed three people with his chainsaw. The tune is beautiful, and if you don't take it too seriously, the lyrics are amusing.

It appears that the Geocaching moderators finally got around to cleaning out their moderation queue, as someone responded to my now-visible post. They said that proxies should work with the Geocaching website as long as they are not anonymizing proxies. That's not particularly helpful considering that the proxy I use *is* one that anonymizes. I have clarified, stating that I do use an anonymizing proxy, and asking again if there is anything I can do about it. To be perfectly clear, I once again stated that taking down or bypassing the proxy is *not* an option.

When I converted Wake Up from FLAC to Vorbis, I didn't really know what the command I entered to do so meant. It included an unneeded sound quality flag, so when I later used the command to convert Woodward's music, I left it out. It kind of bothered me a little, for OCD reasons, so I erased the music on my mobile, reconverted Wake Up, Ashes, and The Beautiful Machine without the flag, and tried to put the music all back onto my mobile. All the music went back on without issue, aside from Sunny Side of the Street. I jumped to the conclusion that MTP had gone back to choking on Are You Having Fun?.ogg's file name, as in the past, I've had issues transferring files with questions marks and asterisks in their names. However, that was not the case. The other tracks in that album would not transfer to the mobile either. I rebooted the mobile, and the whole album transfered without error. I don't know what the issue was, but at least it seems resolved for now.

I downloaded some of Kellee Maize's work, which was sorely missing from my playlist. Namely, I downloaded her three free albums on Jamendo (her other three on Jamendo are proprietary) including her new remix album. I'm not too impressed by some of the remixes of her work. Her original versions are much better, though a few of the remixes are good too. The next albums I buy will probably be her two free albums on Bandcamp (again, the other two on Bandcamp are proprietary). Once I buy those, I can tell her that if she fixes the licensing on the others, I'd have no problems buying and recommending them. Her main website says all her work is under CC BY, so really, it's just a matter of getting her to update to show this on BandCamp and Jamendo.

An old friend, [REDACTED], wrote to me today. He found my new email address, but he used my old PGP key, probably assuming I still have it. Unfortunately, this key was lost when my hard drive failed on me. I've written back explaining such, but [REDACTED] is a cautious individual. We'll have to see how he responds and if he believes that I'm the same person he once knew.

As I said, [REDACTED] uses PGP encryption. To write back, I attempted to retrieve his public key from the key servers using Claws Mail's GnuPG plugin's interface, but it appears such an option does not exist. After searching the web and scouring the interface, I ended up giving up and looking for a new option. I installed Seahorse, which is supposed to be a graphical key manager, but it didn't show any signs that it had actually downloaded [REDACTED]'s key, and the key did not show up in the list of keys I have on my machine. Next, I tried GNU Privacy Assistant. GNU Privacy Assistant throws errors complaining about an unsupported certificate every time I open or close the application, as well as if I access certain dialog windows within the application. If I attempt to download a key, I'm told that on key was found but that zero were downloaded. I decided I might be better off replacing my whole mail client. Back when I used IceDove with Enigmail, key retrieval was possible from within the mail client, so I know it can be done. Additionally, replacing the mail client may allow me to escape pinentry's idiocy. I decided to try Evolution. I installed it, but it doesn't show up in the application menu and running evolution on the command line doesn't work. I went back to the command line to recheck what keys I needed, and found that [REDACTED]'s key was installed. What I figure most likely happened is that Seahorse successfully imported the key, but showed no success message. Likewise, it does not display the key, either due to a bug or due to it not displaying public keys. GNU Privacy Assistant found the key but would not download it because it had already been downloaded by Seahorse.

Speaking of pinentry's idiocy, I'm planning to code a way around using pinentry when compiling my site. Every day I have to deal with pinentry fighting me tooth and nail to make sure I don't paste my password in or autotype it. It is a pain in the butt, and it's all because the developers think everyone should hand type their passwords. I have news though: if your password is as secure as it should be, typing your password is not a real option. I don't know what to do on the mail front. I don't send mail that often though, and most of the mail I receive is automated, so I don't have to deal with pinentry in my mail client on a regular basis.

*Last minute update*: When I was compiling my site today to upload this entry, I found that pinentry's password prompt had changed. Autotype is now completely broken. Before, pinentry would attept to detect if I had autotyped the password, and would claim that the password was incorrect if it successfully detected that I had. Now, autotype doesn't even allow input by autotype. However, it now accepts clipboard input. I can now paste my password! No paste blocking and no complaints about pasted passwords are present. I'm not sure if this is actually not pinentry at all or if something I installed while as a dependency today fixed pinentry's poor behavior. I will have to look more into this next time I have a clean system to work with, so I can try to find exactly which installation fixed the issue.

No one prevents me from speaking my mind today.

*REDACTION*: I have been asked by the entity mentioned above to remove his/her name and not link to him/heron the Web. This is a request on behalf of the person's privacy, and is *not* a request made by a third-party government entity.

Copyright © 2015 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

I forgot to upload my PGP key ...

Day 00038: Tuesday, 2015 April 14

Apparently, I never added my PGP key to the key servers. My guess is that I got distracted dealing with the new pinentry issues. When I first set up my PGP key pair, I was in a rush to get a signed letter sent out. Pinentry was being a major pain, refusing to allow me to paste the password for the key I had *just created* so I could unlock the private key to sign the email with. I spent quite a bit of time finding a way around this antifeature, ant this provided a suitable distraction long enough that I forgot to upload the key.

Seahorse provides the option of uploading your public key to two different servers by default, though more servers can be added pretty easily. The default servers are ldap://keyserver.pgp.com and hkp://pool.sks-keyservers.net. The former refused my key with an error, but the latter took it right away. Note the different protocols on these URIs though. I think the first may have failed because the wrong protocol was being used. This is just a guess and I'm not planning to pursue this, but perhaps editing the protocol on the URI would have fixed the issue.

Today at work, I had my boss attempt to send me an SMS message, which surprisingly came through! Before that, I had tried to send myself an SMS message, but the outgoing message was blocked. I verified the other day that both incoming and outgoing voice calls are blocked. When I was on my way to the credit union today, my data connection went down for a bit, but otherwise, data connectivity has remained intact. In short, I cannot send outgoing SMS, but I can accept incoming SMS, my voice connection is cut off in both directions, and I have full data connectivity. I can't help but feel that my carrier only half-heartedly ended my service. This sort of limbo service status will likely end when the two-month suspension period ends and all chances to reconnect the line are lost, but for now, it looks like I'm still partway connected.

When I was heading out of work today, a customer in our lobby saw the bag that I always carry everywhere, and asked how many pizzas were in it. It was obvious from the shape of the bag that no pizza boxes can fit in it, but I simply replied that I had no pizzas on me. He next asked how many sandwiches I had in the bag. I pulled out the only food I had on me, and said that all I had were my potatoes and vegetables. He asked if why I didn't have food from our restaurant was because I was tired of the food we serve, presumably assuming I eat a lot of our restaurant's food because I work near it. Of course, I explained that, being vegan, I can't eat a single item on our menu because it all has either meat, cheese, or both. He insisted that I need meat, so I explained that I actually feel a lot better now that I don't eat it. He insisted that I need to accept that I am a man, and that men are carnivores. (He said "carnivores", but I assume he meant omnivores; he had ordered a meat pizza which still had both cheese and grain.) He said that eating low-quality meat such as that found in fast food places will make you feel the negative effects, but that quality meat has no such effect. He said that coming from an Italian family, he ate good meat and was better off for it. I'm honestly not sure what being Italian had to do with anything, but he said that people that say people don't need meat are stupid. I couldn't argue my real reason for becoming vegan in front of him given the setting, as I am vegan for ethical reasons. If I were to argue to a customer in earshot of my boss that it is unethical to eat anything on our menu, I would likely be fired. I need to wait until I land a better job to do that. However, the facts are quite simple to me. Animal products such as meat and dairy are not sustainable. I was willing to sacrifice my wellbeing for the greater good of the planet. The fact that my body now feels awesome is merely a pleasant side effect of my actions, not the end goal. If I could feel even better with an omnivorous diet, I still would decline. I choose to be an herbivore, and I do not regret my decision.

After work, I dropped by the credit union to talk to a representative about the fact that my credit card has still not been marked as compromised, despite me having asked for it to be marked as such on the thirteenth of last month. I explained that I needed the card marked as compromised and a new card issued, and that it has been over a month since I asked through the Web interface that this be done. From the actions of the teller, I gather that this is not an action commonly performed for credit union members in person, as she had to call up some other department to ask for instructions on how to do it. Most people probably do this over telephony as recommended, as everyone seems to be married to the telephony system and doesn't see how idiotic such a requirement is. From the sound of it, she was able to immediately cancel the old card number, but she had to put in a request in a note attached to the card cancellation that anew card should be issued. The card people don't seem to be responding to written requests though (in the case of the one I wrote to them, anyway), so it's likely that the compromised number was indeed canceled, but that it could be a few months before the request for a new card is noticed and taken card of. To be honest though, I don't care, as long as the old number is no longer able to spend money in my name. I use cash in person, and my Discover card works most places online in the mean time.

I got home to a message asking that I remove a name and URI from yesterday's weblog entry for privacy reasons, a request that I have complied with.

My mother loves SMS messaging, but it annoys her that I use the SMS gateways whenever possible, as I hate SMS messaging myself. The problem is that on her iPhone, and message going either direction shows up as an attachment on the receiving side. It used to annoy her when her friend with an iPhone would message her, as it would always come through as an attachment, but she decided to get an iPhone herself, and since then, the problem has been happening for messages to or from her through the gateway. As I can no longer send her SMS as she wants, and I had to reply to a message from her using email, I decided that I had better do some research in case an argument came up. I was dead sure that the problem was the iPhone, likely due to Apples goofy iMessage service. As it turns out, I was only half right. First of all, I was right that the problem exists only on the iPhone. However, the problem is Verizon-specific; it doesn't happen with iPhones on other carriers, meaning it isn't because of Apple's goofy iMessage system. To be fair, I don't know anything about iMessage, it was a stab in the dark based on some posts I read that said that users switching away from the iPhone do not receive SMS messages on the new device due to all their SMS messages instead being sent to Apple's servers. Since the iPhone seemed to be the common denominator in all this, and the problem involved SMS, I assumed it was due to the messages not being sent along the route that they should be sent (that is, directly from the carrier to the customer, not from the carrier to Apple, then to the customer), and that this middleman was mishandling the messages. This problem has been going on since at least 2012, and Verizon still hasn't done anything about it. If you check the end of the thread, it's apperent that Verizon got tired of the continued complaints about the issue, but instead of fixing it, they Locked the topic in October 2013 so no more complaints could come in. If you read through the thread, there seems to be good evidence that iOS 5- did not have the problem even with Verizon service, but iOS 6+ does. The fact is, Verizon and an up-to-date iPhone are a losing combination, though I would argue that any device on Verizon or an iPhone on any network aren't a great idea either.

Redactions were made today, but of my own free will, not by government force.

Copyright © 2015 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.1 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

A free Web comic found and a system freed

Day 00040: Thursday, 2015 April 16

I found a Web comic today that is distributed under freedom-respecting terms! Before this, the only Web comics I found that respect freedom are some of Nina Paley's work, such as Mimi and Eunice. It's great to know that more than just one comic artist is not trying to keep a death grip on their work.

I read the prologue, which was a very unnerving and sad story. A society gained global piece and, having no wars to get in the way, was able to also achieve vast scientific knowledge. At this point, they decided to attempt to find other intelligent life in the universe so they could share this knowledge. They find that they are alone in the universe though, unable to find even one sign of intelligence elsewhere. The people fell into despair and many ended their own lives or wandered space aimlessly. Some people instead decided to explore spirituality, and in doing so, they found that they might be able to reach other universes by altering their state of mind. They figured that there were other races like themselves, alone in their respective universes, and wanted to reach out. They make contact with a being of sorts, offering them the final piece of knowledge they are missing, but warning that the knowledge comes at too great a cost and that they should decline the offer. Only after accepting the offer are they told the price. The being says Your price to pay for my knowledge is this: I shall eradicate every one of you. Out of kindness. And sadness. Somehow, this entity believes that erasing them is a kindness. Whatever this knowledge is, I highly doubt it's bad enough for erasure to be a kindness. It also say it will erase them out of sadness, but it seems the main sadness is caused by the erasure itself. The entity says it will miss them, and seems to feel sorrow for the events leading up to this erasure. Why do this people need to be eradicated? I do not understand. I also don't understand how they are related to the actual story, as the story seems to take place in a different universe than the one these people were erased from.

My brother's laptop seemed to have lost a part of the operating system and wouldn't boot any more. We installed Debian 8 on his system, but due to the hardware manufacturers being over-controlling, there was no way to make his wireless hardware work without nonfree firmware. Upon his request, I helped him install this firmware. It wasn't optimal, but it was probably better than wasting an otherwise-good laptop. It's not like fully-free laptops exist yet anyway. While I was doing this though, I made a startling discovery. Last time we did this, we had to enable the contrib repository, which we did so through the Synaptic interface. While the Debian team insists that the contrib and non-free repositories are not a part of Debian proper, Synaptic treats these repositories as special, offering simple check boxes to enable them. This special treatment means that they very much *are* a part of Debian. However, in Debian 8, these check boxes have been removed. These repositories are finally separate as far as the system is concerned, making Debian truly free (for the most part, there are still a couple of other minor issues such as the inclusion of GFDL works as long as they don't have invariant sections). The FSF would argue that because the Debian documentation still explains how to add these repositories to the system and these repositories are hosted on the same servers, that these repositories are still a part of Debian, but I disagree. Free and nonfree things can be hosted on the same server, and the documentation is not part of the system. Then again, the FSF has a lot of wacky ideas like that, such as that nonsoftware doesn't deserve the same freedoms as software. While the FSF has a lot of great ideas, they also have a lot of poor ones, and what they say should be treated as a tool to provoke your own thought processes and decisions, not treated as the absolute truth as if they are some sort of authority. Unlike the FSF-approved distributions, at least Debian recognizes the fact that nonsoftware needs to be under the same freedom-preserving scrutiny as software, and tries to keep nonfree nonsoftware out of its distribution as much as nonfree software.

My canary still sings the tune of freedom and transparency.

Copyright © 2015 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Pinentry came back to haunt me

Day 00042: Saturday, 2015 April 18

I don't know why, but pinentry seems to be in use in my compilation script again. I will go back to the original plan of coding around it. Pinetry is a thorn in my side for no good reason.

When I first set up the weblog ASCII calendar index page, the plan was to have a different index page for each month. As a result, it made the most sense to fill the empty spaces at the beginning and end of each month with days from the preceding and following month, as that provided links to more total pages. However, with all the ASCII calendar pages now being shown on the same page, all it's doing is creating redundant links and making it a bit harder to understand the navigation page. I've now fixed that, so ASCII calendar pages only display days actually appearing in the months the represent.

I'm not sure what is up with my mother, but she was trying to buy herself, my sister, and I each a new used computer. It makes sense that my mother and sister need new machines. My sister's laptop has a broken hinge and I think it is starting to have issues. My mother's machine has a virus, and it has been locked up for months. We can reinstall the system, but because my mother runs Windows, the Microsoft DRM is likely to give us problems upon reinstallation. She told me to pick one out too though. I tried explaining that it seemed like a waste of money seeing as my computer is still functional, but she insisted. The main thing that got her to stop was me telling her that after buying the computer, the first thing I would need to do with mine is wipe the system and install a system that I could actually use (the computers on display all ran Windows or OS X). I explained that until we got it home and wiped the system, I had no way to know if the hardware was compatible with Debian. Once the system is wiped, we likely cannot take it back. The people at the recycling center said that they some times have Zorin OS, but that they are usually netbooks. My understanding is that netbooks are fairly useless for most tasks and that they really only work well as a way to access Web-based applications. There's also the fact that Zorin likely includes proprietary firmware, so Zorin running on a machine is no indication that Debian likely will. We were told though that if we came back at a time that both the pricing guy and the custom machine building guy were in (Monday through Thursday, excluding this coming Thursday), we could look into having a custom Debian machine being built. I don't need a new computer at the moment, but it seems I might be getting one anyway, depending on how much my mother pushes.

My canary still sings the tune of freedom and transparency.

Copyright © 2015 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

My camera bugged up on me

Day 00043: Sunday, 2015 April 19

For some reason, the game Flare is not in my brother's Debian repository, but it is in mine. We are both running Debian 8, though I'm on the 32 bit version and he is on the 64 bit version. I can't seem to find any rhyme or reason. I get booted from OFTC whenever I join the network, so I'm not able to access #debian-next to inquire at this time. My brother unfortunately wants to switch to Ubuntu, citing that it is "easier to use" due to the inclusion of the Ubuntu Software Center. Personally, I had issues with the Ubuntu Software Center back before I discovered freedom. Namely, many packages wouldn't show up in it, or if they did show up, would only show up on some installations. More importantly, there's the issue of Ubuntu activating the nonfree repositories by default. It seems there's no talking him out of it though, and it's his machine to decide what to do with.

I've found that lately, my Replicant device's camera doesn't focus like it used to. Photographs all come out blurry and the manual focus option doesn't appear to work. I tried hitting the "rotate camera" option (not thinking it would help focus, but to test it none the less), and the whole camera application quit on me, stating that it couldn't connect to the camera hardware. Starting the camera application again made it automatically shut down again with the same error message, and rebooting didn't help. I thought I would have to wipe the device to fix the camera, and feared even that might not help. However, simply wiping the camera application's data solved the problem. As I write this paragraph, I tried the camera again, and it is focusing perfectly. I'm not sure what determines if it will focus or not. Perhaps it is the lighting?

I took a few days off from dealing with political issues, but it seems that the ISPs are at it again. I'm told they have issued a total of five lawsuits and counting, and are additionally trying to convince Congress to repeal the FCC's decision using a Congressional Review Act.

I'm considering setting up a Web design operation here, or possibly at a new domain. I don't have time to start on the designing at the moment, but I looked into getting a certificate that won't throw errors in Web browsers. I tried to register an account with StartSSL, but their server seems to be having issues at the moment.

My canary still sings the tune of freedom and transparency.

Copyright © 2015 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.1 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

It wasn't pinetry that was the problem, but KeePassX all along

Day 00045: Tuesday, 2015 April 21

The Cricket rebate card came today. It seems they did send it this time. Maybe they did send it last time too, and it was just bad luck that it never arrived, but I cannot say for sure. There is still that lady I talked to that prompted me to even talk to Cricket about the issue in the first place, after all. No one she knew was recieving their cards unless they pestered Cricket about them. There's also one of my bosses, who also was promised a Cricket rebate card. I talked to my boss today, and she said that Cricket was playing games with her and refusing to send her card.

The fact that they send cards that expire in a few months is also kind of lame. My guess is that they are counting on people not spending them in time, so Cricket gets to keep the remaining balance at the end. They probably also do it so they can charge merchants a processing fee for each purchase you make with the card. There's also the issue of cards making it easy to track you, though I doubt this was a major consideration for Cricket. It's possible that they want to see what you are buying so they can sell that information to advertisers, but I think the transaction fees and expiring funds are the most likely reasons for this behavior. In any case, I cashed my card's full funds out right away, so there will be no spend tracking (aside from tracking me to the location I made the withdrawal at) and no expiration of funds.

It seems that pinentry is not actively trying to detect and reject password autotyping after all. Instead, the issue lies in KeePassX. KeePassX is trying to use at least two different keyboard layouts, presumably GB and US. I have no idea why it sometimes uses one and other times uses the other, but this is why pinentry sometimes accepts the autotyped password andothertimes does not: sometimes the correct passowrd is entered and other times it is not! After running setxkbmap gb on the command line, KeePassX behaves, and pinentry cooperates.

I still think it was a poor design choice to prevent pinentry from allowing passwords to be pasted into the prompt, but I can live with that as long as I can autotype instead.

My brother read the ingredients list on the vegetable oil spread I've been using, which is something I apparently failed to do. The bloody stuff contains *milk*! I haven't wanted to admit it to myself, but I haven't been feeling great over the past week or so. I bet it's this stupid "vegetable oil spread" that has me feeling down. I need to remember to read the ingredients on *everything*, even if it seems obvious that it is vegan-friendly. I'm vegan for environmental reasons, but the truth of the matter is that I discovered when I went vegan that milk has a very negative effect on my moods and energy levels.

Josh Woodward released another song today! It's called Aimless, though I think it was mis-uploaded. It's a lovely tune, but it appears instrumental. The song page includes lyrics, so until I'm told otherwise, I have to assume the track was supposed to contain Josh singing those lyrics. I let him know of the error, so we'll see what he says about it.

My canary still sings the tune of freedom and transparency.

Copyright © 2015 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Stressware, a coming free OS distribution.

Day 00046: Wednesday, 2015 April 22

My website is currently set up kind of poorly. When updating it, I have to recompile every page on the entire site. As my weblog increases in size, the amount of time it takes to compile the site is also predictably extended. Now that compilation is no longer a pain as the PGP password entry issue is cleared up, the next logical step in building this site is to fix the build process so the site doesn't need to be completely rebuilt when updating.

Another important thing to add here is OpenID management. I'd love to be able to host my own identity here. The php-openid package might be a good place to start as it is included in the Debian 8 main repository and should be easy to install.

Last night, I told my biologist sister what I learned about human fingers and muscles, and she said that she was aware of the muscles embedded in the skin that are used to cause goose bumps, but was unaware that no other muscles are present in the fingers. She continued that goose bumps are actually useless in humans. She said they are used to raise hair and trap air to create better isolation during cold times, but that human hair is to sparse to trap any air and create this isolation. Wikipedia backs this up, adding that goose bumps are also used to make one look bigger and more intimidating, which again, doesn't work with sparse hair.

I've been speaking with a Jehovah's Witness for months now, and he's been trying to convert me. Sometimes, I have wondered if maybe he is right, but other times, his stories are either inconsistent with themselves or are inconsistent with science, despite his initially telling me that Christianity does not contradict science. However, among other things, if we were created and not evolved, why do we have useless reflexes? I've been thinking about it today, and the fact is that we have muscles embedded in our skin and the sole purpose of these muscles is to enact our vestigial goose bump reflex. If someone created us, why would our bodies contain oddities that serve no valid function for us but do serve a valid function for other animals? The only logical explanation for human goose bumps that I can think of is that we evolved from something with more hair, but that the goose bump reflex was not detrimental enough to our survival that natural selection would have selected against it.

I've decided not to inquire about the band Lo-Fi is Sci-Fi. The band broke up a while ago, separating into its component band members Marc with a C and Chris Zabriskie. My guess is that keeping the Lo-Fi is Sci-Fi work up was costing them money and not bringing in a lot due to no new music being released. I'm only guessing that not much money was coming in because the site was taken down though. For all I know, it could have been removed for other reasons. Asking these people to bring back their work is selfish on my part, and I should instead spend my money on musicians that are still active as to encourage them to continue producing music.

I checked on my credit union credit card finally over the Web interface, and it appears that the old number has indeed been canceled and a new one instated. The new card has not yet arrived by mail, but I'm in no rush. As long as the old number no longer works, I'm happy.

JSavage brought Stressware back to my attention on #nottor. Last I knew, Stressware had not yet been fully-liberated, and it sounds like this is still the case. The main page on Stressware says the project aims to meet the FSF's flawed definition of a free distribution, but the mission statement adds that, unlike the FSF definition of a free distribution, Stressware requires nonsoftware to be free as well, making it completely free (once the liberation process is complete). It seems that Xfce and KDE's Plasma Desktop are not yet included in the distribution, but their inclusion is less important than the removal of the nonfree junk. I've downloaded it and will probably try installing it in AQEMU tomorrow. It will be nice having a second free option available when choosing a system. Stressware will probably act very similar to Debian due to them being built from the same components, but package management will obviously be different. If it turns out to be better for my use case, I may switch my main system over to use it once it is freed and contains Xfce (or I find another suitable desktop that Stressware does contain). As far as I know, Stressware is only available over onion though, which may make it inaccessible for some users.

My mother was contacted by the people who had her iPhone today. They claim that they bought the iPhone from the actual thieves, but she says they were acting very shady and suspects them of being the thieves themselves. It cost her $50 USD to get the device back from them and the SIM card is missing, but it is now back in her possession. I tried explaining to her that she needs to now report the device as found and then have me swap the SIM card over from the device she has been using over to the new device, but last I heard, she was talking to the Verizon people trying to get them to switch the plan back to her iPhone without the SIM card being moved over. If they do that, her mobile plan will be transfered back to the stolen SIM card and neither of her devices will be connected to the network. Whatever. If she and Verizon get it straitened out, no worries, and if she instead needs my help, I'll get her to switch the plan back to the SIM card she just probably had the plan switched away from and I'll move the SIM card over as I said needed to be done in the first place. I think part of the problem is that she doesn't even know what the SIM card is, as she has admitted.

My canary still sings the tune of freedom and transparency.

Copyright © 2015 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Don't vote for Ron Wyden

Day 00047: Thursday, 2015 April 23

Our idiotic Senate Finance Committee just voted to enact the Trans-Pacific Partnership, which will keep the public in the dark about corporate trade agreements. This is not acceptable. My own state's Ron Wyden was one of the people to vote "yes". As a constituent, I've written him a letter of disapproval in hopes that he revises his vote.

I forgot to check my mail last night before turning in. Josh Woodward fixed the song download, so now lyrics are included in the track. I half expected him to say it was an instrumental piece, but in that case, why would lyrics be included on the page? As I hoped, it was just a simple upload mistake, and it's fixed now.

It seems a group of homophobes wet up an Anti-Gay Day. Come on, people. Why do you care what other people want to do do in their own bedrooms? It's not like the gays are trying to force these people to be gay with them. If someone was trying to get me to have gay sex with them, I would be opposed to that. Then again, if someone was trying to get me to have strait sex with them, I'd be opposed to that as well. But if gay people want to be gay with other gay people, who is really hurt by that? No one. It's not even like being gay is a choice. If they were to choose to pretend not to be gay, they likely wouldn't find happiness. What right do these people have to deny gay people happiness?

I just learned that I may have a mild case of trypophobia. I didn't even know there was a word for that. From the Wikipedia article, is seems that many people have it way worse than I do, as patterns of holes in just about any object seem to be able to trigger the creeped-out feeling and I only really have this happen if I think the object is animal flesh of some sort. For example, the babies embedded in a surinam toad's back totally weird me out, but honeycomb has no effect on me. Furthermore, I only cringe a bit, but it sounds like some people even have panic attacks.

I finally added the cover art to the Josh Woodward albums that were missing it. On his website, Josh has both thumbnail images and full-size images of his album covers. I chose the thumbnails because on my monitor, they looked slightly larger than what I needed. The main place the covers show up is on the album select screen, where they are laid out in rows of two. However, once I had the thumbnails on my mobile, I found the images were both blurry and pixelated due to being smaller than I had thought. Not only that, but I realized that the artwork also shows up filling most of the screen in some cases. I wouldn't really mind, the blurry images stand out next to all the clear, crisp album covers from other artists (and Josh's "Ashes" and "The Wake" albums which, having their artwork embedded in the files, are also clear and crisp). I switched to the full-size album covers, which look much nicer.

I stumbled upon a free, zero knowledge, encrypted, cloud-based password manager and "e-wallet" called Encryptr. If my understanding is correct, both the server and client are free, so I could run my own server instance if I got the client running. The Android client seems to be only on Google Play though, putting it out of reach for the time being. If I ever get my build environment functioning, I could build the client myself, but for the time being, that isn't an option. Speaking of which, I should try again to get the Replicant build environment to work at some point. It seems there is desire to get Encryptr added to F-Droid, but due to the funky build process, there's been a snag. I can't help be be reminded of the EFF Alerts application build issue.

It seems that running setxkbmap gb only fixes KeePassX until the next reboot, so it should be added to ~/.bash_aliases or somewhere else that will be run on login. Actually, now that I think about it, ~/.bash_aliases might not be run until you open a command prompt. I'll have to keep an eye out next time I reboot to be sure.

My canary still sings the tune of freedom and transparency.

Copyright © 2015 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

The merger is off!

Day 00048: Friday, 2015 April 24

Comcast is giving up its plans to merge with Time Warner. This is awesome! Both Comcast and Time Warner are known for having over-priced yet poor service. Their ability to stay in business despite this is likely due to their monopolies in their respective areas. They are the only major cable providers in the country, and they have vowed not to overlap their territories as to avoid competing with one another. Both companies are far too powerful and have shown that they have no plans to use this power for good. In addition to generally ripping off customers in terms of service quality and price, they are even attacking net neutrality. Had these two companies merged, they would have combined their power and become an even worse threat to the Internet and to customers. The next thing that needs to happen, of course, is that these companies need to be further split, breaking up the monopolies in the areas they already control.

I've updated this site's build script to permit updating to accommodate new pages without rebuilding the entire site. To force the recompiling of a given page that already exists without recompiling the whole site, the given file can be deleted before the build script is run. Any pages that exist in the source code but do not exist in the compiled copy will be built. In addition, all indexes will be rebuilt in case new pages have been added to the directory they represent. The canary page will be updated when the --canary flag is used with the script. All other paged will be left alone.

I bought Kellee Maize's Age of Feminine album today, mostly to get my hands on a copy of the Struggle track. PayPal was being a pain again, but after about five attempts to use the same credit card, they finally accepted the card. Bandcamp allows you to send a note to the artist if you buy an album, so I took the opportunity to point out that Age of Feminine and Aligned Archetype are available under reasonable licenses CC BY-SA and CC BY,respectively), but Owl Time and Integration are both under licenses that disallow modification and sale (CC BY-NC-ND). I then politely asked if she would consider releasing those two under CC BY-SA or CC BY. Assuming the note reaches her, I think there is a high probability she will go for it, as her website lists all of her albums as being covered by CC BY (so though no actual downloads are available in a place that lists all of them under that license, it is probably her intent that they all be free).

I also took the opportunity to download most of Mate's music (everything except the single proprietary album). I can't find a place to buy his music, but it is beautiful and I appreciate him making it available My favorite of his songs is probably Ellen. Apparently I'm not the only one to like that song either, as his newest album is mostly remixes of that song. I'd love to hear what people have done with the song tonight, but I have work early tomorrow and should get to bed.

I was in a meeting today advocating a bond be granted to the Marcola school district to be used to tear down their quite literally hazardous old elementary school and rebuild it up to code. The school has broken pipes, a heating system that is unsafe for them to even turn on, and it sounds like the school is in several buildings, which they fear is too hard to keep safe with modern creeps running around. It sounds like they need the money pretty badly, and they say now is a great opportunity due to low interest rates, but the question is this: why are people so short sighted that they won't put the money toward these sorts of things *before* they are needed? If the money was stashed away beforehand, the interest could be used as an asset instead of a hurdle. To be clear, this isn't the school's fault. From what I understand, it's the taxpayers' fault for waiting until the last minute to even consider having their taxes raised. By being so short-sighted, they are insuring that they actually have to pay *more* than they otherwise would have had to.

Copyright © 2015 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

On the mend

Day 00051: Monday, 2015 April 27

I'm feeling much better today. I still don't really want to do much here at home, but I got through work without any exhaustion or desire to go home early.

Josh Woodward responded to my inquiry about his Aimless video, though he didn't tell me what format it is in like I asked. He said that the video "just a regular YouTube video", which unless YouTube has it's own format, is not a file format. To the best of my knowledge though, YouTube doesn't have a seperate file format than everyone else because it would be inefficient to have a YouTube-only format. Instead, YouTube allows the uploading of several standard formats. I will not push though. As far as I know, I'm the only one having this issue, and I prefer Josh's music in Vorbis format on my mobile anyway. He keeps FLAC files on his site of all his recent work and most of his earlier work, and converting FLAC to Vorbis is a trivial task (I had already done it long before he responded). As long as I have the FLAC/Vorbis files, I'm happy, and if his other fans are able to access the video, that should be enough.

Apparently, there is a chance of the electoral collage votes to be distributed more fairly in my home state of Oregon. People are trying to set it up so our votes actually count. It's not as good of a solution as disbanding the electoral collage altogether, but it's a start. If you care about the votes of Oregonians, please send a letter to the people in power. It sounds like they are trying to get this implemented in all states, not just mine, but I need rest and will not be looking into this tonight.

I received a letter yesterday when I was lying in bed sick instead of processing email. This letter warns that the a Fast Track overturning of net neutrality is in the works. No petition or letter-writing campaign is attached, but maybe that was an oversight and one is coming. If this Fast Track repeal of net neutrality goes through, we will lose the free Internet here in the States.

It appears ~/.bashrc isn't run until the command prompt is opened, so putting setxkbmap gb in there only acts as a shortcut to fixing KeePassX's key mapping. I removed the line from ~/.bashrc, put a script in ~/bin that fixes KeePassX's key mapping then starts KeePassX, and put a modified menu item file at ~/.local/share/applications/keepassx.desktop. However, .desktop files don't seem to treat the ~/bin directory as being in the $PATH variable. It was easy enough to fix by specifying the full path of the script, but I might want to look into what determines the $PATH as seen by .desktop files later.

My canary still sings the tune of freedom and transparency.

Copyright © 2015 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Please declassify the text of the Trans-Pacific Partnership!

Day 00052: Tuesday, 2015 April 28

I'm tired of messing up the entry numbers on my weblog. Whenever I mess one up and don't notice, every entry after it also gets messed up, as I don't remember the entry numbers myself. I just look at the previous day's entry number and assume it to be correct. I've now built a function to do the remembering for me. It takes a year, month, and day number and returns a string containing the entry number and date formated the way I head my entries. It's a bit vain for me to set up a function that takes into account the day that my personal weblog was started, but it will save me a lot of time and effort. As an added bonus, if I ever change my heading format, it can be uniformly changed across my entire weblog now without much additional effort.

President Obama is claiming that people calling the Trans-Pacific Partnership a "secret" trade deal are being dishonest, and that the people need to look at the facts. However, the fact is that the public of the United States is not allowed to see the details of the deal and therefor cannot know if the deal is good or bad. Senator Warren called him on that, and is attempting to get him to declassify the agreement. Until he does so, it it is fact a secret agreement, and cannot be assumed to be in the best interest of the people. In fact, if the deal *was* in the best interest of the people, there would be no reason to hide it. Please help get the details of this agreement exposed by signing the petition.

I seem to have broken several pages lately. Mistedwind keeps running across them and sending bug reports, which is very helpful, but some of these bugs should have been caught by me as soon as the pages were uploaded. At the very least, when I update a page, I need to verify that the page actually renders. I obviously can't proofread and spell check everything after rebuilding every page on the site, but rendering shouldn't take too long to check.

My canary still sings the tune of freedom and transparency.

Copyright © 2015 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.1 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Encryptr and a service plan, both for my mobile

Day 00053: Wednesday, 2015 April 29

We need to continue encouraging out lawmakers to vote against the Trans-Pacific Partnership fast track bill. It is a secret trade deal, and as such, is not likely good for the people. If it was good for the people, it wouldn't need to be kept secret from us.

The Encryptr developer (Devgeeks) got back to me about downloading the Android APK outside of Google Play. Replicant lacks access to the Google Play Store, and even if it did have access, the required Google Play Store application is untrustworthy due to no source code being available and the application forcing automated updates of itself and the also-proprietary Google Play Services application. Honestly, it's not safe having either of these on your device. I would compile Encryptr myself, but every time I've tried to get the Replicant development environment set up, some thing has gone wrong. Now that I have the download page, I can begin setting up the server. It seems there is no PowerPC Debian package, but Debian is much easier to build for than Replicant/Android. I should be able to compile Encryptr when time allows.

Because I want a data connection on my mobile but have no interest in having a telephone number, I started looking into getting a tablet plan on my "non-tablet" mobile. The truth is that smart "phones" are computers, not telephones, making them very much like tablets. However, carriers don't like to admit that, because they like to tack on an extra fee for voice and SMS services, even if you never use them. I talked to a representative in T-Mobile the other day though, and he said he could set me up with a tablet plan on my "non-tablet" mobile. Assuming he can and will actually do this, the price of the plan would be $20 USD per month. I talked with a T-Mobile representative over the Web, and she said the tablet plans have limited high-speed data but unlimited low-speed data. I use mostly text-based protocols, so low-speed data works just fine for me. The fact that I'll only go for a prepaid plan my prevent the guy in-store from helping me though. He may be willing to help me get a tablet plan in an effort to gain another postpaid account, but be unwilling to help for prepaid plans. I've noticed that the T-Mobile representatives try to push the postpaid plans as much as they can.

MetroPCS has a better tablet plan, having 2 gigabytes of high-speed data (compare to T-Mobile's one gigabyte) for only $15 USD (compare to T-Mobile's $20 USD, unlimited low speed data, and unlimited SMS. I'm not too excited about the SMS part seeing as I have a strong distaste for SMS messaging, but I don't have to use that part. The real catch with this plan is that there is a $3 USD fee to pay your bill in person. I'm not the only one to find this ridiculous. You can bypass this fee by paying online, but that requires a credit/debit card and removes any hint of anonymity. Quite frankly, that's not worth it. Having an added fee to pay your bill though is ridiculous. There does seem to be a way to avoid the fee by using a special drop box, though I'm not sure money in a drop box can be trusted as a method of making sure your bill is paid. An employee could easily steal the money, and as you have no receipt or other confirmation of the payment until later, they could claim your payment never came in. No contact information is presented online aside from a telephone number. There is no support email address and no Web support option. I will have to walk into the store in person tomorrow to inquire about the idiotic fee. Another lovely antifeature is that third-parties can charge to your account unless you specifically tell MetroPCS not to allow third-party charges.

I tried to find some metal music on Jamendo today, as one of my bosses is really into power metal. I figured we could both enjoy the album with it being metal for him and free for me. I found an album I though sounded awesome, but my Jamendo Vorbis-downloading plugin was failing to acknowledge the album. I tried several other albums, most of which registered with the plugin just fine, but there was a second album that the plugin ignored. I tried restarting the browser and clearing the cache several times, but the plugin always ignored those two albums. I tried finding the download URI by hand, but that didn't work either. I've come to the conclusion that some albumsarenot offered in Vorbis form in any way on Jamendo, and that is sad. It's bad enough that you have to jump through hoops to get vorbis albumsthere at all, but to have some completely unavailable is quite disheartening.

My canary still sings the tune of freedom and transparency.

Copyright © 2015 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

MetroPCS refuses to provide tablet service to "non-tablet" mobiles but Cricket supplying me with gratis data seems to be intentional

Day 00054: Thursday, 2015 April 30

I watched a video that put up some very good arguments against the death penalty. It's a shame that the video is proprietary, but I felt it was an important enough issue that it warranted linking to the video anyway. It seems there is no logical reason to instate a death penalty. The only "benefit" it provides is emotional closure for families.

My mother showed me that she bought some vegan butter today. I had personally already given up on vegan butter with it being too expensive, but it was a highly-appreciated gesture. She seems to be being a lot more sportive of this than I would have thought. She does still seem to have issues with my sister's vegetarianism though, which still baffles me.

I walked into two MetroPCS stores today. Both claimed the $3 USD was somehow justified, but couldn't really explain how. They basically repeated a few times that this is just the way they do things. Both locations also said that they do not have a drop box, so there is no getting around the three dollar fee without a deanonymizing credit or debit card. This point is moot though, as the MetroPCS representatives refuse to provide tablet plans for "non-tablet" devices. As the do-it-yourself method tends to require entering an IMEI, after which the system only allows you to choose a plan the company wants you to have for that device, the only way to set this up would be to either have a tablet to start the plan on before swapping the SIM card on or get a representative to set up the plan for you. If the T-Mobile representative will still help me in a couple months when I need the new plan, I will choose the T-Mobile $20 USD tablet plan from them. When I eventually have to replace my Replicant device, I might choose a tablet to avoid this sort of discrimination. The larger size would be a pain potentially, but if I can find a big enough protective case and get pants and shorts with bigger pockets, it may be doable.

I checked in on my Cricket account to see if I could get the date that they plan to cut me off entirely. I couldn't find the date, but I did find a notice about my account:

Suspended Accounts

When your account is suspended, you need to make a payment to reactivate your service. Until you reactivate your service, you can't complete the following tasks:

Make or Receive calls
Send or Receive Text, Picture or Video Messages
Add a Line
Upgrade Device
Get a New SIM Card
Turn On/Off Auto Pay
Reset Voicemail Passcode
Change Plans or Features
Change Profile Info (phone number, email)
Change Password
Turn On/Off Online Security with Account PIN

There is no mention of cutting off my data access, so it appears it was intentional that they didn't do that. On the other hand, it was unintentional that they did not cut off my incoming SMS. The representative I spoke with said that to cancel my Cricket account, all I had to do was quit paying, then wait through the two-month suspension period. If Cricket wants to provide me with gratis data access during this two month period, who am I to complain?

My canary still sings the tune of freedom and transparency.

Copyright © 2015 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.